all right I'm talking to Mike pelts
right now a raw natural powerlifter and
he just gave me the coolest uh grip
exercise that I had never even thought
of so uh here's Mikey uh he's going to
show you uh and everyone can do this
it's just using a bench so Mikey take it
away yeah basically what you're doing is
you want to get your thumbs over
concentrate on every finger being
squeezed as hard as you can uh hold that
for 30 second intervals and I mean just
squeeze as hard as you can making sure
every finger is working and uh yeah I
started doing these I got to give credit
to Matt Omen one of our younger guys
who's super is double overhands 500 like
it's nothing and not double overhand
means deadlift de he deadlifts with
double overs 500 no problem yeah and
know without without even chalking up
first I looked at it and I said well you
know he probably has big hands well my
hands go like this over his so I'm like
that's not it so when I saw that I said
okay whatever he does for grip I'm going
to start doing it and and I've only been
doing it for a few weeks and my double
overhand deadlift on uh you know 405 is
like nothing now I can do reps with it
before it was really tough uh and I can
notice that I'm holding everything a lot
easier plus doing it this way you don't
chew your hands up so you can kind of
come back and grip something tomorrow so
the hands stay healthy they don't get
chewed up now uh Mike tell us what set
sets and Reps you yeah basically what we
have what we do is we'll do five sets of
30 second holds close and and make sure
real quick see those thumbs make sure
you wrap those thumbs over and you're
just do an ISO holds for 30 seconds at a
time so you'll do how many sets that
like that five sets five sets of how
many seconds uh 30 seconds five sets of
30 seconds like that and then out wide
same thing so you'll do five sets of 30
seconds out wide and when you start you
might just want to do you know gradually
build up you might just want to do one
or two sets and then get up to five sets
but what's the purpose of doing a
narrower and a wider grip well when you
do that narrow grip it hits more you'll
feel it on this side of your forearm so
you're kind of getting more of the
outside fingers and then when you go on
a wider grip you're really hitting the
inside fingers so you're going to feel
it more on the forearm and here so it
kind of hits both ends of the spectrum
and I mean it really I think it really
works it's one of the best things I've
started doing so yep and we were just
talking about how important the the grip
is for deadlift if you have the perfect
pull and then your grip strength isn't
that big of a factor but if if you get
off at all if you you know if the
deadlift gets off you better have a
strong grip that final few inches if
your grip is lacking you're screwed yep
all right thanks Mike appreciate it